nextdoor.com 2017-12-02

# Nextdoor | Privacy Policy

### Nextdoor Privacy Policy

Welcome to Nextdoor! We invite you to read this privacy policy, which describes our privacy practices, including how and when we handle the member and visitor information collected and created through your use of Nextdoor.

#### What is this document?

This policy is a part of the Nextdoor member agreement, and it controls over any conflicts with that agreement. Please read this policy carefully. By visiting, joining, or using Nextdoor, or otherwise indicating that you agree to this policy, you consent to and authorize our using your personal information as described in this policy. If you don’t consent to us using your information as described, please stop using Nextdoor and, if you are a member, delete your account. Please [contact us](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/emails/new?) if you have any questions or concerns.

#### Who or what is Nextdoor?

Nextdoor is the private social network for neighborhoods; we hope that neighbors everywhere will use the Nextdoor platform to build stronger and safer neighborhoods around the world. We use “Nextdoor” here to refer to the Nextdoor.com website and our iOS and Android apps (also referred to as our “Services”) that provide you with access to that platform. We also use “Nextdoor” to refer to the companies operating our Services.

If you live in the United States, the Services are operated and provided to you by Nextdoor.com, Inc., 875 Stevenson Street, Suite 700, San Francisco, CA 94103. If you live in the EU or elsewhere outside the United States, Nextdoor is operated and provided to you by Nextdoor EMEA Limited, an Irish registered company, 6th Floor, South Bank House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. Non-US visitors and members, please refer to “Export of Data”, below, to see how Nextdoor protects data originating outside the United States. Not all Nextdoor account types and features are available in all locations; click here for more information about what is available where you live.

#### What are Nextdoor’s rules and expectations about member privacy and information?

Nextdoor can be a great way for members to come together and build community. To make it work, we have some clear ground rules and expectations about member information and privacy: 

  * Don’t share your neighbors’ information or non-public Content without their permission. 
    * It’s important to Nextdoor that neighbors should be able to communicate privately amongst themselves; that’s why we restrict who can access your neighborhood. 
    * If you take information or Content shared by one member to another member and share it outside the neighborhood(s) without their permission, you are violating your neighbors' expectations; that behavior is a serious breach of trust. 
  * Don’t share your personal account with someone else. 
    * It’s important to Nextdoor that members be who they say they are. If you share your account, it’s not clear who is behind your name. (We make an exception for Local Pages and similar specialized accounts, since a business or news organization may need to authorize more than one person to manage its account.) 
  * Don’t gather information from Nextdoor, either manually or using automation (such as through scripts, robots, crawlers or spiders). 
  * We know that you do not want spam or marketing phone calls from third parties, so we will never sell or rent your personal information to third parties, and we won’t share it with a third party unless we have your authorization. Similarly, it is never OK for you to give, sell, rent, or otherwise share your neighbors' information from Nextdoor to third parties. 

Violating any of the above or other aspects of the Nextdoor Member Agreement may lead to a loss of account privileges, potentially including a permanent ban from Nextdoor.

### What information does Nextdoor collect, and how?

Nextdoor collects information a few different ways:

**We collect information from you, when you give it to us directly or give us the OK to get it from another source.**  
For example, when you register for Nextdoor, you voluntarily provide your name, profile photo, email address, and similar information. Here are some other ways that you might provide us with information:If you decide to invite new members to join Nextdoor, you might share their residential or email address with us, or share your contacts with us, so we can send an invitation and follow-up reminders on your behalf. 

  * If you want to join Nextdoor but we don’t yet have service for your neighborhood, you might give us your contact information and ask us to notify you when we do. 
  * If you use Facebook to register for or log in to Nextdoor (or later connect your accounts), you authorize Facebook to share your personal information with us, including your email address and publicly available information about you and your Facebook friends. 
  * If you want to support a local business, you might share information about it, in the form of a Recommendation or by creating a Local Page, where available. (Not all Nextdoor features or account types are available in all locations.) 
  * If you want to help your neighbors and Nextdoor get to know you better, you may share information about yourself in your profile — your interests, skills, or even what you love about your neighborhood. 
  * If you want to communicate with your neighbors and share Content (as defined in our member agreement), you might post something on Nextdoor. 
  * If you want to allow us to show you where you are on your neighborhood map, to tag your posts, photos and events by location, to verify your address (where available), or to display activities and Content that may be relevant to your current location, we may ask your permission to access geolocation information from your mobile device. 
  * If you contact us with a support request or comments, you may provide us with your contact information and a description of the issue so we can respond. 

**We collect information from your browser, computer, or mobile device, which provide us with technical information when you use Nextdoor as a visitor or member.** Like nearly every other online service, we automatically collect technical information created when you visit or use Nextdoor or read a message from us, including: 

  * Device data, which tells us about the device you’re using: what type and model it is, its operating system and version, its unique identifier, crash data (if applicable), and what settings you’ve enabled. Your device and software settings affect what information your device makes available to us. 
  * Log data, which is automatically recorded by our servers based on data sent by your app or browser. This typically includes the date and time you visited, the browser or app version you used (and its settings), the URLs you came from and go to, your IP address and protocol, and how you used Nextdoor (for example, which links you clicked on). 
  * Cookie data, which comes from “cookies” (small data files stored on your computer or mobile device) and similar technologies. Cookie data helps us recognize you, remember your preferences, and learn more about you; some, but not all, cookie data is associated with your Nextdoor account. You can configure your browser to reject cookies, but doing so will prevent you from logging into our website. To learn more about our use of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies, click here to read our Cookie Policy.

**We collect information from our vendors and, in the US, from advertisers.** For example, we obtain map information from mapping companies, and an advertiser may provide us with information about whether a sponsored post on Nextdoor led to purchases.

**We collect information from from public sources, such as census data, street addresses, property lot maps, and postal address change information.** This helps us understand our members and potential areas for expansion.

### How do we use the information we collect?

We use information to identify and invite potential new members, and to set up new Nextdoor neighborhoods. 

  * If you decide to invite new members to join Nextdoor, you might share their residential or email address with us, or share your contacts (or social-media friends list) with us, so we can send an invitation and reminders on your behalf. 
  * We use public sources to help identify potential new members (well, technically, addresses not already associated with a Nextdoor membership); and, on rare occasions, use that information to send direct-mail invitations. 
  * If you register or log in via Facebook, we may give you the option to invite your Facebook friends to Nextdoor. Those friends will see some information about you along with your invitation. 
  * If you ask us to notify you when we start offering service to your neighborhood, we keep your request until your neighborhood is established, and then use it to notify you as requested and to help verify you as a resident. 

We use information to get you started on Nextdoor: 

  * For residential members, we verify that you live at the address you gave us through a combination of your address and a second factor, such as a code we provide you, digits from your credit card or social security number (where permitted by law), or manual verification by the member who invited you or by a Lead. We also use public registries to block addresses of registered sex offenders in the United States (and other countries where permitted by law). 
  * We may notify Leads of new members as they join the neighborhood, and Leads may be able to see all neighbors’ addresses, regardless of their display settings. To learn more about Leads, [click here](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/topics/326511-nextdoor-leads/articles). 
  * If you sign up via Facebook or connect your accounts, we use your Facebook information to automatically create your Nextdoor account, populate your profile, and request a password, so you can log into Nextdoor in the future without connecting through Facebook. 
  * Once you register, your personal information is used to populate your profile. 
  * We use business information to create Local Pages, which help members learn about the businesses in their communities. To claim your Local Page, click here. 
  * For business or other special accounts, we may verify your address using third-party or publicly available sources, such as business listings or your website. 

We use information to operate Nextdoor and to improve our products and features: 

  * To help you publish Content and view and respond to Content from other members, based on your settings and posting selections. 
  * To highlight popular neighborhood topics or resources on a neighborhood’s public home page or an organization’s public page. 
  * To help support businesses recommended by Nextdoor members. 
  * To understand the aggregate demographics of the members and neighborhoods we serve. 
  * To respond to your support requests and comments. 
  * To test and evaluate potential new products and features on Nextdoor. 
  * To diagnose and resolve problems, analyze trends, and monitor aggregate usage and resource needs. 

Where available (currently, only in the US), we use information to provide and improve sponsored posts and other commercial offerings. Privacy is an important tenet on Nextdoor, so we do not give your personal information to advertisers without your authorization. Rather, we use information: 

  * To measure whether a sponsored post was interesting to members. 
  * To measure whether a sponsored post was effective for the advertiser. 
  * To help target offers and other ads, based on what we think will be interesting to you. 

### What choices do you have?

We work to give you control over what and how you choose to share on Nextdoor.

You have choices about sharing your profile information: 

  * You decide how much personal information, such as the street number of your home address, to share in your personal profile, and how much of your profile to share with different audiences (such as members in your neighborhood, or members of nearby neighborhoods), by using your profile settings. 
  * If you want to share information about your family in your profile, such as photos, please ensure you have their permission. 

You have choices about invitations and reminders: 

  * If you aren’t a member and don’t want to receive invitations or reminders, please [contact us](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/emails/new?) to opt-out of future email invitations or reminders or to ask us to amend or delete any personal information about you. 
  * If you ask us to notify you when we start offering service to your neighborhood, we keep your request until your neighborhood is established, and then use it to notify you as requested and to help verify you as a resident. If you change your mind about wanting to be notified, [contact us](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/emails/new?). 

You have choices about whether, how, and with whom you share Content: 

  * You can share Content with other Nextdoor members, in the form of a private message from you to another member, or a post shared with your neighborhood, or nearby neighborhoods, or with a Group. Some types of Content, such as Events, Classifieds, and Recommendations, may be shared more widely across Nextdoor or as “public,” meaning accessible to search engines and non-members. Use your settings and the selections available when you post Content to control visibility. 
  * Comments tagged to a business, including positive comments which may also be marked as Recommendations, are viewable on the business’s Local Page and will be automatically shared with the business, unless you opt out of sharing. If a Lead or our system tags a comment incorrectly, you can correct it; check your settings for other choices about visibility. 
  * If a business you recommend advertises on Nextdoor, your Recommendation may appear in, near, or adjacent to sponsored posts or other advertisements from the recommended business. If you do not want it used this way, you can opt out by removing (“un-recommending”) it. 
  * Replies (other than Recommendations) and “thanks” in a conversation are visible to the same Nextdoor neighborhoods as the original post that started the conversational thread. 
    * This means that a reply to a broadcast post from a news organization or a governmental agency, such as a police or fire department, will be visible across its service area, potentially covering multiple neighborhoods or an entire city. If the agency or news organization accounts makes their broadcast feeds available to non-members, your reply may be accessible to non-members as well, attributed to “A member from …” (the name of your neighborhood) without other identifying information. If you do not want your reply to be accessible to non-members, you can delete it. 
    * If a reply is tagged to a Local Page as a Recommendation, visibility is based on your Recommendations privacy settings. 
  * You can edit your posted Content or delete it from Nextdoor as long as your account is active, with the limited exceptions noted below. 
    * Private messages from you to a specific member or members cannot be individually deleted, whether from your side or from the inbox of the recipient(s). (If you delete your account, private messages are deleted, along with all of your other posted Content.) 
    * If you’ve shared Content with a group, you cannot remove it from the group recipients. 
    * If you’ve moved neighborhoods, you cannot delete any Content you shared in your old neighborhood, but we can delete it for you; [contact us](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/emails/new?) for assistance. 
    * Please note that deleting a post will result in removal of all replies to that post too. 
  * If you believe that an item of de-identified or aggregated public Content visible to non-members (for example, a snippet on your neighborhood’s home page) is yours and do not wish it to be publicly visible, contact us. 
  * To learn more about communications and visibility, visit [Nextdoor Help](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/articles). 

You have choices about the emails and notifications we send you: 

  * You can manage your email preferences on your settings page. By default, you are signed up for agency broadcast emails applicable to your area; you can change this in your settings. Certain member-related administrative emails cannot be turned off; the only way to end those is to delete or deactivate your Nextdoor account. 

If you granted Nextdoor access to geolocation information from your mobile device, you can revoke that grant at any time by changing the settings on your mobile device.

You may choose to move your account to a new neighborhood, or to deactivate or delete your account: 

  * If you move from one neighborhood to another, and indicate through your account settings that you have moved, some of your personal profile (such as name, photo, interests, responses to your invitations, phone and email contact) will migrate to the new neighborhood. Once you’ve verified your new address, you will no longer be a member of your old neighborhood and cannot edit or delete Content you posted there. Content items in the old neighborhood will link to a limited user profile that includes your name and photo. We may notify the neighborhood Leads of your move and let you do so as well. 
  * You can deactivate your account through your account settings, with immediate effect; to request reactivation, you simply log back in to Nextdoor and indicate that you wish to reactivate. 
    * Account deactivation ends all email notifications; you will no longer appear in your neighborhood directory or map. We may notify the neighborhood Leads that you’ve left the neighborhood, and/or give you an opportunity to do so. 
    * Content you shared before deactivating will remain in your neighborhood, attributed to a limited member profile with your name and photo, except for any individual Content items you deleted before you deactivated your account. 
  * To request deletion of your account, please contact us at deletion@nextdoor.com; account deletion may take up to forty (40) days. Account deletion cannot be undone. 
    * Account deletion ends all email notifications; you will no longer appear in your neighborhood directory or map. We may notify the neighborhood Leads that you’ve left the neighborhood, and/or give you an opportunity to do so. 
    * Account deletion deletes all of your previously posted Content and all data relevant to you except that: (a) private messages may remain visible to the recipient(s) but attributed without your identity (e.g., “A Member”); and (b) we may retain account records to the extent we believe necessary for legal, safety, or other legitimate reasons. 
    * Because deletion removes your account information from our systems, you may in the future receive new invitations to join Nextdoor. 

### How does Nextdoor share information about me with third parties?

Nextdoor is a platform for neighbors to share helpful information with each other. To that end, we make the Content you post on Nextdoor, such as posts, replies, messages, and profile information, available to other Nextdoor members based on the preferences in your settings, the preferences on the Content you provide, and as described in this policy.

As we’ve said above, we know that you do not want spam or marketing calls from third parties, so we will never sell or rent your personal information to third parties, and we won’t share it with a third party unless we have your authorization.

_A few words about advertising:_ With respect to advertisers on Nextdoor in the US (and elsewhere when available), you always have a choice as to whether or how you interact with a sponsored post or other advertisement (for example, by replying or “thanking” them for the post or by clicking to learn more about an offer). If you reply to a sponsored post or other offer, we send your reply to the advertiser, and we may log your interaction as part of tracking the overall effectiveness of the ad.

We may customize the sponsored posts or other ad offerings you see on Nextdoor based on information from our advertisers, on the demographics of your neighborhood, or on your actions on Nextdoor. (For example, a home services company might prepare a de-identified scramble, or hash, of customer addresses, to allow us to match that with a similarly de-identified scramble (hash) of addresses of members on Nextdoor, and use that to offer a special deal to those customers who are Nextdoor members. Or, if you search on Nextdoor for a particular product, we might show you ads for providers of that product or related products.) In the future, we may also offer ads that are personalized based on your actions off Nextdoor; if we do this, we will provide you with notice and choices about it.

Our systems are not currently configured to accept browsers’ “Do Not Track” signals, as no industry-wide standard for handling them has been adopted.

In the future, we may offer you a feature that allows you to use your Nextdoor account credentials to log in to someone else’s services, apps, or websites. If you opt in to use this feature (for example, to sign a local petition), then with your permission, Nextdoor will provide the other service with your personal information, such as your name, address, and neighborhood. Their use of this information, and other data about your use of their service, will be governed by their privacy policy.

In the future, we may present you the option to purchase goods or services through a third-party payment processor. If you choose to make a such a purchase, we may share your information with the payment processor as necessary to conclude the transaction, as well as with the company or person you’re buying from. Any information that you provide for sharing for this purpose will be subject to their privacy policy.

We share some aggregated information about our neighborhoods with government agency members and other organizational members, such as statistics about neighborhood activity and size. Because of the special role played by government agency accounts, we may provide agency accounts with limited identifying personal information (first name and last initial) for neighborhood Leads, so that the agency can communicate directly with them.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information with companies we do business with, including our advertisers (in the US or where available) as well as government agency members or other organizational members.

In limited circumstances (for example to highlight popular neighborhood resources or topics on the neighborhood’s home page), we may make snippets of Content available, without your name or other identifying information, to the public (meaning non-members and search engines).

We may share your personal information with third-party service providers doing work for us. These third parties are contractually required to use it only to provide their service to us, and contractually barred from using it for their own purposes. (For example, we use a company to help test and analyze the performance of our website and mobile applications.)

We may share your information within our “corporate family”, meaning Nextdoor.com, Inc., the company that provides Nextdoor in the United States, and its subsidiary Nextdoor EMEA Limited, an Irish registered company, which provides Nextdoor in other countries, to help provide, maintain, and improve Nextdoor. As we grow and Nextdoor becomes available in more countries, we may expand our corporate family by establishing local subsidiaries or other affiliates in these countries as needed to help us provide Nextdoor there. Upon or in anticipation of the merger or acquisition of our company and/or all or part of its assets, your personal information may be transferred. If you have questions about the Nextdoor family of companies, [contact us](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/emails/new?).

_FOIA/Sunshine Laws._ Posts by government agency accounts, and your replies to those posts, may be subject to laws mandating public access to government records (such as the Freedom of Information Act/FOIA or state "sunshine" laws).

_Legal and Safety Reasons._ We may retain, preserve, or share your personal information if we have a good-faith belief that (a) we are legally required to do so in response to a legal request (e.g., a subpoena, search warrant, court order, or other request from law enforcement) or (b) that it is necessary or appropriate to do so to protect our rights, property, or safety; to enforce our Member Agreement or any other agreements we have with you; or to prevent physical injury or other harm to any person or entity, including yourself and members of the general public. Our legal team reviews every request received from law enforcement, and we frequently seek modifications of requests that we believe are procedurally flawed or too broad.

### What else should you understand about your information and Nextdoor?

_Data Retention._ We may retain your information in our server logs, our databases and our records for as long as necessary in light of the purposes set out in this privacy policy, subject to any legal obligations to further retain such information. We may retain your verification-related information for a reasonable period of time, even if you do not complete all verification steps, to assist with future verifications and to prevent abuse of our verification processes. If you decide not to verify the account and would like us to delete the verification information you provided, [contact us](https://help.nextdoor.com/customer/en/portal/emails/new?).

_Account Security._ Nextdoor uses technical and organizational measures intended to keep your data secure, including using https on our web pages to reduce the risk of unauthorized interception of your communications during your visits to the website. However, the internet is not a fully secure environment and we cannot guarantee that your personal information won’t be intercepted or improperly accessed. Please ensure that you keep your password safe and do not share it with anyone.

_Accessing Your Information._ You can access much of your Nextdoor information by logging into your Nextdoor account. For EU members: If you require additional access or if you are not currently a Nextdoor member, email us at personal-info@nextdoor.com to request a copy of your Nextdoor information.

If you live in the United States, the Services are operated and provided to you by Nextdoor.com, Inc., 875 Stevenson Street, Suite 700, San Francisco, CA 94103.

If you live outside the United States, the Services are operated and provided to you by Nextdoor EMEA Limited, an Irish registered company, 6th Floor, South Bank House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

_Export of Data (Non-US Residents)._ For the purposes of the EU Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC), Nextdoor EMEA Limited is the controller of the personal data of non-US members and visitors collected, used and shared through the Services. Nextdoor transfers personal data outside the EU in accordance with the Directive. For example, Nextdoor may use a legal mechanism known as “standard contractual clauses” to protect EU personal information transferred outside the EU. Standard contractual clauses refer to contracts between companies transferring personal information (for example, from Nextdoor EMEA Limited to Nextdoor.com, Inc.) that contain standard commitments approved by the EU Commission protecting the privacy and security of the information transferred. If you are a non-US member or visitor, then by continuing to use Nextdoor, you authorize us to transfer and store your data outside your home country, including to and in the US, as described in this policy. The privacy protections and the rights of authorities to access your personal information in some of these countries may not be the same as in your home country; Nextdoor will only transfer personal data as permitted by law, and will take steps intended to ensure appropriate protection of your personal information. If you have questions, please contact us.

_Other Services and Websites._ In using Nextdoor, you may come across links to websites and services operated by third parties (for example, if a member shares a link to a video on YouTube). These third parties have their own privacy policies, which will apply to your activity if you click on the link and access their website or service. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for such external sites’ privacy and security practices.

_Amendment._ From time to time we may make changes to this privacy policy. If we materially change our privacy policy, we will take steps to notify you in advance of the change, for example by emailing you or by posting a notice in your neighborhood feed. The most up-to-date version of the privacy policy is available here. If you continue to access or use Nextdoor after the date any revised privacy policy comes into force, you will be deemed to have consented to the revised privacy policy.

**Contact Us**  
Email: [privacy@nextdoor.com](mailto:privacy@nextdoor.com)  
Nextdoor.com, Inc., 875 Stevenson Street, Suite 700, San Francisco, CA 94103. Phone: +1 415-569-7971. Fax: +1 415-488-5949. Email: privacy@nextdoor.com.  
Nextdoor EMEA Limited, 6th Floor, South Bank House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

_Last updated: Feburary 3, 2017. Effective date of update:_

  * _February 3, 2017 for all new members signing up on or after that date_
  * _March 3, 2017 for pre-existing members_

_For previous version (available until March 3, 2017),click here._
